Jose A. Villena

9081 SW 124th Street Cell: 786.251.1153 Miami, Fl., 33176

Email: jvillenaiv@gmail.com

SENIOR TECHNOLOGY EXECUTIVE CIO • CTO

An accomplished senior information technology executive with over 35 years' experience of proven success in the development and execution of strategic technical and operational initiatives. A results-oriented professional, recognized for taking on large projects and excelling through the creation and utilization of emerging technologies and methodologies. A visionary leader able to adapt to highly volatile and mission critical environments, while remaining energized, pragmatic and focused to achieve bottom line success. In-depth technical and operational experience acquired in startup, growth and institutional organizations within a diverse set of industries.

Core Competencies

- Executive Leadership / Communications
- Team Mentoring and Instruction
- Budget Management and Cost Control
- Strategic Technology and Business Planning
- Disaster Recovery and Risk Assessment
- Global Strategic Alliances

- Global Product Management
- Performance Measurement and Analysis
- Technology and Application Development
- · Architecture and Infrastructure Planning
- R&D Full Development Life Cycle
- · Legal and Regulatory Compliance

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lumos Consulting Group, Miami, Fl.

2008 to 2018

Co-Founder, President and Chief Executive Officer

Lumos is a boutique software development and consulting company which provided global software solutions for Subway Corporation; a recognized leader in the fast food industry.

Led the Lumos team in the design, development and support of the production point-of-sale (POS) software menu management system for more than 40,000 restaurants spread across 106 countries and 6 continents between March 2008 and September 2018. Responsible for all aspects of menu creation and distribution to Subway POS systems. Additionally, responsible for the collection of all POS activity, including transaction detail, and the distribution of this critical information to multiple corporate partners in near real-time.

- Negotiated contracts with Subway in excess of \$20M over term of engagement.
- Led Lumos collaboration with senior Subway management team to develop strategic business and technical requirements.
- Led Lumos team of 10 senior developers and engineers responsible for the design, architecture, development and support of SubEx and HomeOffice a custom, menu management, web application suite comprising 108 projects. Scope of work included the creation and management of: Inventory, Recipe and Sub-recipe, Menu Items (PLUs), Promotions, Menus, Taxes and other critical aspects of the POS systems localized in 32 languages.
- Licensed the Lumos Data Distribution System (LDDS) to Subway as the integration platform for restaurant POS systems and the menu management suite which enabled the near real-time collection

and distribution of sale transactions, cash drops, labor timesheets, cash drawer reports, weekly reports, etc. Typical daily volume of transactions exceeded 13M / day.

Homexperts, Inc. dba Homekeys, Miami, Fl.

2002 to 2008

Co-Founder and Chief Information Officer

Homekeys was a developer, integrator and provider of web-based information tools and services for the real estate industry. It was the creator of the ValueSearch® platform; a web-based search technology combining map-based search, ortho-satellite imagery and proprietary automated valuation algorithms to provide unique value-based search and filtering capabilities.

Served in multifaceted capacity within Senior Executive team, providing strategic leadership and critical operational direction to drive technical innovation. Responsible for technological vision of Homekeys; reporting directly to the CEO with direct reports including VP Research and Development.

- Instrumental in raising \$9M of private equity financing.
- Developed strategic plan to align technological initiatives with mission critical business goals.
- Full responsibility for the design, development, installation and operation of all internal and external information technology systems, including \$2M point of presence in Terremark NAP Miami, Fl.
- Full responsibility for operation and management of all business support systems including: CRM, messaging, content services, etc.
- Designed, developed and implemented disaster recovery environment to fulfill 24x7x365 production availability requirements.
- Full responsibility for research, development and quality assurance functions.
- Outsourced non-critical development functions for cost control to meet budget limitations.
- Negotiated contracts for the acquisition of real property data throughout the state of Florida.
- Established data warehouse for all real property and real-estate listings in the state of Florida.
- Principal inventor of ValueSearch[®], a patent-pending search technology for the real-estate industry.
- Principal inventor of patent-pending valuation methodologies for forecasting home values at time of sale.

CellIT, Inc., Miami, Fl. 1996 to 2002

Co-Founder and Chief Technology Officer

CellIT was a communication system inventor and developer. Its products were distributed in the Americas, Europe, Africa and Asia. In 2001 it was acquired by Contact Center technology industry veteran Davox Corporation to form Concerto Software. Concerto is known today as Aspect Software; the leading force in the Contact Center industry with over 5,000 site installations worldwide.

One of two internal voting members of the Board of Directors and reported directly to the CEO. Direct reports of two VP Research and Development, VP Engineering and eight Directors and over 60 indirect hardware and software engineers. Annual operating and capital budget of \$10M.

- Instrumental in raising over \$37M of private equity financing.
- Instrumental in articulating strategic technology direction which led to merger with Davox Corporation.
- Chief architect and inventor of CCPro®, which is the current codebase for the global flagship contact center offering of Aspect Software.
- First in industry to physically separate common control from TDM switch function (see patent below).
- Full responsibility for all research, development and quality assurance functions.
- Invented and developed MaPP®, an internal contribution and feedback application to manage and monitor the full development life cycle and product roadmap.

Outsourced non-critical development functions for cost control to meet budget limitations.

- Negotiated all alliances, domestic and international, for software and hardware products integrated in product suite.
- Collaborated with VP Sales and Marketing and with VP Product Management for global product positioning and management.
- Provided Executive level sales support for large enterprise accounts.
- Directed and developed technical training programs for internal and partner support organizations.
- Principal inventor of blended call center agent functionality (inbound / outbound). Patent 6775378 filed Oct. 25th 1999 and awarded August 10th 2004.
- Principal inventor of skill-based routing in the call center. Patent 6832203 filed Nov. 5th 1999 and awarded Dec 14th 2004.
- Principal inventor scalable non-blocking architecture in the call center. Patent 7230927 filed Dec. 7th 1999 and awarded June 12th 2007.
- Voting member ATM Forum UNI and VTOA working groups.

FiberTel, Inc., Miami, Fl

1994 to 1996

Co-Founder and VP Engineering

FiberTel was a systems integration company specializing in the deployment, management and support of enterprise voice and data networks. In its first two years, it reported revenue of \$7.8M and had 20 full-time employees including management. Merged into CellIT to provide technical and installation support for call center operations.

Member of the Board of Directors, reporting directly to President. Expert in voice and data network architecture and technology specializing in campus and multi-site medical enterprises and call centers. Typical project in excess of \$2M and included all LAN and WAN enterprise systems and subsystems.

- Instrumental in raising over \$6M in private equity financing.
- Chief architect and network engineer; responsible for all statements of work.
- Full responsibility for all research, development and quality assurance functions.
- Developed custom CTI applications to meet enterprise customer requirements.
- Designed, supplied and managed installation of the fiber optic campus and premise cabling system for Indian River Medical Center in Vero Beach, Florida.
- Designed, supplied and managed installation of the data network security, switching, routing and management systems for business and medical applications (X-ray imaging) in Indian River Medical Center.
- Designed, supplied and managed installation of the voice and data network security, switching, routing and management systems in 9 sites for Vitas Healthcare in southern California (San Diego – Los Angeles).
- Designed, supplied and managed private inter-site voice and data network in southern California responsible for cost savings in excess of \$800k annually for Vitas Healthcare.
- Designed, supplied and managed installation of the voice and data network security, switching, routing and management systems for Precision Response Corporation i4 centers supporting 4000 agents.
- Provided pre and post-sales support.

Vitas Healthcare, Miami, Fl.

1992 to 1994

Telecommunications Manager

Vitas Healthcare, a subsidiary of Chemed, was the nation's largest provider of end-of-life care serving over 60,000 patients a year. It employed over 5,500 professionals in 16 states at the time.

Selected in national search for a critical enterprise project. Project included the creation of a national private network to interconnect 16 sites across 6 states for the proprietary clinical assessment and electronic patient record application. Contracted for 2-year term; compensation included all graduate school expenses; reporting directly to Director Information Systems. Direct reports included installation and support supervisors and application developers.

- Designed, solicited and negotiated national, multi-year, inter and intra state, private network contract.
- Eliminated all enterprise inter-site long distance voice switched services and costs.
- Designed and managed the installation and replacement of all voice call processing (PBX, voice mail, IVR, DACS, etc.) systems across all sites.
- Designed and managed the installation and replacement of all data communication (switches, routers, gateways, etc.) systems across all sites.
- Designed, solicited and negotiated all voice and data equipment contracts and maintenance agreements.
- Successfully created and unified all inter and intra site voice and data communications while reducing the total enterprise telecommunication recurring costs.

University of Miami, Coral Gables, Fl.

1982 to 1992

Senior Systems Engineer - Telecommunications

With more than 13,000 full-time employees, the University of Miami was the largest private employer in Miami-Dade County at the time.

Held several positions, including entry level technician, culminating in Senior Engineering status. The University supported 12 different colleges and schools offering 114 bachelors, 104 masters and 57 doctoral areas of study at the time. The diversity, quality and quantity of administrative, academic, research and residential technology utilized across 3 main campuses rivals that of any enterprise or municipality. Reported directly to the Telecommunications Manager and direct reports included engineering and software development staff.

- Managed and certified broadband coaxial cable system for the delivery of CATV, SDLC, Ethernet and Token Ring for Coral Gables campus data network.
- Architected, designed, and created the RFP and managed the installation of \$25M fiber optic campus ring and premise cable system for the Coral Gables (main) campus.
- Designed, created RFP and managed the installation of \$8M fiber optic campus ring and premise cable system for the Marine campus. NOAA on Key Biscayne was included in the ring.
- Responsible for all data communications systems and subsystems in the Coral Gables campus.
- Responsible for all administrative data communications systems in all campuses.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration (MBA) University of Miami, Coral Gables, Fl.